

#### CONTACT

PHONE: +91-9753750955

SKYPE: ambujdubey or ambujdubey@outlook.in

#### WEBSITE:

https://ambujbpl.github.io/

#### **GITHUB:**

\_(https://github.com/ambujbpl)

#### EMAIL:

ambujdubey89@gmail.com

#### **Linkedin**

https://in.linkedin.com/in/ambuj-dubey-2923b456)

# **AMBUJ DUBEY**

#### **PROFILE**

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 4.5+ years experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Certified in both Front-end and Back-end technologies. Having hands-on experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. Played major role with technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize CSS, React, React Native, NodeJs, Strapi, EJS, Php Core, MongoDB, MySQL and MsSQL.

I prefer challenges that require me to work on projects in which I have to work outside my comfort zone and knowledge set. Learning new languages and development techniques are important for me as well as my organizations growth. I worked with AWS, Azure, Heroku, Digital Ocean and others cloud services skillfully.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

### Full-Stack Developer at Logikview Analytics 2019-Now Indore

- Collaborates with development team which includes Product Manager, Software Engineer and Quality Assurance team to identifying software problems, testing methods, and best solutions.
- Developed full-stack applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Integrated app-based solutions with databases, file systems, and cloud-based systems.
- Object-Oriented Analysis.

### Junior Full Stack Developer at Ideata Analytics 2018-2019 Indore

- Developed software applications with technologies like Nodejs, Strapi, Express.js and integration with REST APIs for ADFS services, live tracking application and other services.
- Managed, optimized, and updated databases as necessary.
- Collaborates with development team and created testing methods.
- Object-Oriented Analysis and Relational Database Systems.
- Testing the designed unit test case.

#### Software Developer at Greenticks 2018 Bhopal

- Worked as a Full stack software developer.
- Provided expert technical advice and guidance on projects.
- Created the architecture for software also provided hosting solution and strategize with clients to create software that solves business problems.

### EDUCATION C-DAC

Hyderabad 2016 74.00 %

**Master of Technology** OIST Bhopal / RGPV Bhopal 2013 - 2015 86.00 %

#### **Bachelor of Engineering**

TIEIT BHOPAL / RGPV Bhopal 2007 - 2011 70.59 %

#### **Higher Secondary**

Government School For Excellence, Hoshangabad(MP) 2007 77.40 %

#### **High School**

Government School For Excellence, Hoshangabad(MP) 2005 82.20 %

#### Software Developer at Mobigesture 2016 Hyderabad

 Worked as front end developer with special expertise in Responsive Web Design by using Bootstrap3 framework.

#### **SKILL SET**

Technical skills - Web Performance, Responsive Web Design, Automated Testing.

Programming languages - JavaScript, C Language, Core Java.

Frontend Technologies - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap framework, Ajax, JQuery (JavaScript library), AngularJS (limited), Bower, Webpack, Json.

Backend Technologies - Node.js, Express.js (Server-Side JavaScript Framework), Strapi, PHP.

Database Technologies - MySQL (RDBMS), MongoDB.

Operating System - Linux & Windows Operating System.

Tools Used - WebStorm, Sublime, Atom, Eclipse, EyeQueue, GitHub, Bitbucket, Visual Studio Code, DbVisualizer, FileZilla, Robo 3T and Postman

Communication Tools - Trello, Clockify, Dropbox, Pivotal Tracker, Slack.

Others Skills – Single sign out (oAuth), Payment gatway (stripe), Webhooks implementation, MLab, Heroku Platform, Web-Hosting, Mocha Unit test in Node.js, Wordpress CMS Hosting.

#### **PROJECTS**

Project Title:	Game reporting
Duration:	8 Months
Team Size:	3
Technology:	React Native, MSSQL, EXPO, Android App, IOS App, Azure.
	SSO and SMS API integration
Project Description:	This is a mobile application for reporting a bird hunting game.
Role:	Full stack software developer.

Project Title:	Bail Management system (BMS)
Duration:	Aug 2018(Present)
Team Size:	2
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MSSQL Server, Bootstrap, DataTable, NodeJS, Strapi. Azure, Azure Function, Scheduled Notification, Corp Authentication
Project Description:	Tool provides platform as a single point of access to Datasets in open format published by Ministries/Departments.
Role:	Full stack software developer.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Professional) Hindi (Native)

## GENERAL PROFICIENCIES

Creative Team Work Willingness To Learn Dedication in work

#### **HOBBIES**

Internet Surfing Sports Activities Learn New Technologies

#### **Personal Profile**

Father's Name : Mr. Shravan Dubey Mother's Name : Mrs. Kalpana Dubey

Date of Birth: 06-08-1989 Nationality: Indian Permanent Address: 20-A

Sachchidanand Nagar, BHEL, Bhopal

(M.P.)

Project Title:	Open Data portal
Duration:	Aug 2018(Present)
Team Size:	2
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MSSQL Server, Bootstrap, DataTable, NodeJS, Strapi.
Project Description:	Tool provides platform as a single point of access to Datasets in open format published by Ministries/Departments
Role:	Full stack software developer.

Project Title:	BDA project
Duration:	2 years
Team Size:	5
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Java, AngularJS, AWS Redshift Nodejs, MySQL, Bootstrap, JUnit test, D3 JS, C3 js , Echarts JS, Apache Spark, AWS RDS, Shell Script, Data Visualizations, Heroku.
Project Description:	Tool provides an easy to use analytics platform for users to ingest, clean, prepare and analyze data with visualizations, and help to create reports.
Role:	Full stack software developer.

Project Title:	Track And Trace Project
Duration:	2 years
Team Size:	2
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MySQL, Bootstrap, DataTable, NodeJS, Java, Scheduled Jobs (CronJobs), excel sheets, Node- Mailer, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Nginx.
Project Description:	Tool provides higher level of tracking system of individual shipments and creates a detailed dashboard also send alert when status of shipment gets changed.
Role:	Full stack software developer.

Project Title:	Mobibuzz project
Duration:	4 Months
Team Size:	3
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MongoDB, Node.js, Bootstrap.
Project Description:	This project helps to track employee login, logout time, employee detailed profile, it consist Leave Management system and it also track employee status and company events.
Role:	Front end developer.

Project Title:	KnoahsARK 360
Duration:	5 Months
Team Size:	7
Project Description:	KnoahsARK enables client to manage the entire customer contact center environment by integrating locations, staff, departments, tools, data points and processes to give you one view towards making better decisions
Role:	Front end developer.

Project Title:	VHT project
Duration:	7 Months
Team Size:	5
Project Description:	VHT use to recognized the severity of customer frustration in relation to delivering exceptional customer service. This led to inventing a patented solution, VHT Callback, which eliminated wait time while increasing customer satisfaction.
Role:	Developer (Language Method and grammar Developer, tested method by using JUnit test cases, Automate entire development by using Cucumber and ruby and run it into Jenkins).

Project Title:	ITI Jobs Portal project
Duration:	2 Months
Team Size:	2
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Nodejs, MySQL, DOM, AJAX, Json, Bootstrap4.
Project Description:	Tool provides ITI related database. Here, users can manage, store, share and disseminate information about placement, ITI collages, and its having high level monitoring.
Role:	Full stack software developer (End to end product development with Responsive Web Design by using Bootstrap4 framework).

Project Title:	Greenticks project
Duration:	2 Months
Team Size:	1
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Nodejs, MySQL, MongoDB, DOM, AJAX, Json, Bootstrap 4, Mocha unit test, Webpack, Wordpress4.7, MLab, Heroku.
Project Description:	Tool provides computer based online exam details along with Invigilator details and track daily report.
Role:	Full stack software developer.

Project Title:	Aerotic Project
Duration:	2020(present)
Team Size:	2
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Core PHP, MySQL, DOM, AJAX, Json, Bootstrap 4.
Project Description:	Tool provides product details and also generate daily invoices. It also provide reminder for the customer.
Role:	Software developer.

Project Title:	Harshuj
Duration:	2020(present)
Team Size:	2
Technology:	HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Core PHP, MySQL, Composer, DOM, AJAX, Json, Materialize- CSS, Digital-Ocean.
Project Description:	Tool provides one destination for many applications like contacts, reminders, to-do-list, useful weblinks, notes, feedback etc.
Role:	Full stack software developer.

### **SKILLS**

# - 3 SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

